Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, 1976-1992
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, 1976-1992
Mus. Arc. 1.8
Mikhashoff, Yvar, 1941-1993
2 boxes (39 items)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection contains thirty-one video and eight audio recordings on video cassettes, most with Yvar Mikhashoff present as performer. One video title is missing, represented only by photocopied leaves of the container.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the estate of Yvar Mikhashoff, 1993.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternative Form Available
The collection was digitally reformatted in 2015. The funds for the reformatting were generously supplied by the Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music.
Reformatting consisted of transfer to DVDs for the video content and CDs for the audio content. It also resulted in digital files formatted as preservation archival masters, production maters, and service copies. All digital files are stored in the UB Institutional Repository along with the metadata files created through the reformatting process.
Biographical Note
Yvar-Emilian Mikhashoff was born Ronald MacKay in Troy near Albany, New York in 1941. He began piano studies with Betty Weir and Stanley Hummel in Albany. At the Eastman School of Music in 1959, he first took a major in composition and cello, then changed to piano studies with Armand Basile. In the 1961 academic year, he studied piano at the Juilliard School in New York City. He also had a career as a ballroom dancer from 1962-1965.
In 1964 Mikhashoff entered the University of Houston for studies in piano with Albert Hirsh. He earned a B.M. in 1967 and continued with graduate study in composition with Elmer Schoettle and obtained his M.M. in 1968. It was during this period that MacKay adopted his grandfather's name, Mikhashoff.
Receiving a Fulbright scholarship in 1968, he studied the music of the French Impressionists with Nadia Boulanger. After his return to the United States, Mikhashoff entered the University of Texas at Austin as a doctoral candidate in composition and studied with Hunter Johnson, Kent Kennan, Janet McGaughey and Karl Korte. He earned a Doctor of Musical Arts degree with a major in composition and a minor in literature in August 1973 and founded the Cambiata Soloists ensemble. In the fall of 1973 Mikhashoff was appointed Assistant Professor in the Music Department at the State University of New York at Buffalo. Based in Buffalo until his death in 1993, Mikhashoff had an international performing career which led him to promote new music and American music around the world.
Mikhashoff had a genius for programming, a talent he utilized extensively while organizing many festivals and broadcasts of new music throughout the world, including his work at the Almeida Festival in London and the Holland Festival. Mikhashoff co-founded the North American New Music Festival in 1983 with Jan Williams and remained a co-director until his death. He commissioned works from such notable composers as John Cage, Lukas Foss, Otto Luening, Poul Ruders, James Sellars, Christian Wolff, and many others. One of his most notable commissioning projects occurred in 1982 when he commissioned or solicited new tangos for solo piano from an international array of more than 80 composers. Mikhashoff also edited publications of music, including works by Henry Cowell, Lejaren Hiller, Conlon Nancarrow, and Virgil Thomson. He recorded on the New Albion, Mode, RCA Victor, CRI, and Spectrum record labels. Yvar Mikhashoff's support of contemporary music continues today through the Yvar Mikhashoff Trust for New Music which was created by his estate to support composers and performers of new music.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains thirty-one video and eight audio recordings. The contents are a mix of Mikhashoff's own performances, compilations in which Mikhashoff performs only a part of the whole, thirteen tapes of concerts given at the North American New Music Festival (Buffalo, New York), tapes sent to Mikhashoff by other performers or composers, and films by Lawrence Brose. The eight cassettes containing only audio are from recording sessions in Norway.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as originally processed.
Container List
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 1, 22 June 1976, 1 U-Matic cassette 20 minutes; Title on container: Theatre piece - John Cage Live performance of John Cage's Theatre piece as produced by William Kirkpatrick. Recorded at unknown location. Performers: William Kirkpatrick dancer and director, and others, possibly Yvar Mikhashoff and Frances Marie Uitti Durations: 23:18 Not very good quality. Stationary camera from a bit of a distance. (Box 1, Item 01)
  Contents: Cage, John: Theatre piece
  Digitized copies:
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_001_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_001_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_001_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 01
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 2, 22 June 1976, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: Theatre piece: J. Cage performance Live performance of John Cage's Theatre piece as produced by William Kirkpatrick. Recorded at unknown location. Performers: William Kirkpatrick dancer and director, and others, possibly Yvar Mikhashoff and Frances Marie Uitti Durations: 23:05 Duplicate of Item 1. Not very good quality. Stationary camera from a bit of a distance. (Box 1, Item 02)
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_002_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_002_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_002_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 02
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 3, September 1985, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: 1985 NOS - Ijsbreker Nederlandse Omroep Stichting (NOS) television broadcast directed by Klaas Rusticus, titled De Ysbreker about the Ijsbreker festival in Amsterdam. It includes interviews with director Jan Wolff and composer Louis Andriessen, with studio performances of music by Heppener, Veldhoen, Nancarrow, and Glass. Spoken word by Wolff and Andriessen in Dutch. Recorded at Amsterdam (Netherlands). Performers: Jane Manning, soprano; Nieuw Ensemble, conducted by Ed Spanjaard; Frances Marie Uitti, cello with Judith Hamer, dancer; Balletstudio of Maureen Kramer; Hugh Davies; Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Durations: 1:00:01 Label on tape: NTSC (Box 1, Item 03)
  Contents: Contents include: Heppener, Robert: Memento; Veldhoen, David: Eidofoon; Davies, Hugh: Shozyg sequence, no. 2; Nancarrow, Conlon: Tango?; Glass, Philip: Modern love waltz
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_003_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_003_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_003_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 03
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 4, November 1985, 1 VHS cassette E-120; Title on container: Nederland-C N.O.S. TV Nov. 85, De Ysbreker, copy Nederlandse Omroep Stichting (NOS) television broadcast directed by Klaas Rusticus, titled De Ysbreker about the Ijsbreker festival in Amsterdam. It includes interviews with director Jan Wolff and composer Louis Andriessen, with studio performances of music by Heppener, Veldhoen, Nancarrow, and Glass. Spoken word by Wolff and Andriessen in Dutch. Recorded at Amsterdam (Netherlands). Performers: Jane Manning, soprano; Nieuw Ensemble, conducted by Ed Spanjaard; Frances Marie Uitti, cello with Judith Hamer, dancer; Balletstudio of Maureen Kramer; Hugh Davies; Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Do not reformat - duplicate PAL; mono sound (Box 1, Item 04)
  Digitized copies: Not reformatted.
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 5, 23 September 1986, Video cassette missing; 3 photocopied leaves; Title on photocopy of container: 1986 Thomson and Satie Recorded at Merkin Concert Hall (New York, N.Y.) Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano; Virgil Thomson, narrator There is no original tape. (Box 1, Item 05)
  Contents: Unknown
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 6, June 1987, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: Vienna Now BBC Program, June 1987 BBC TV: Vienna Now. Likely the following about the Almeida Festival, from a BBC description: Vienna Now: Introductory Film Every summer, the Almeida Theatre in Islington plays host to one of Europe's most adventurous music festivals. This year its main theme is the music of Vienna today, and the city's leading composers, Friedrich Cerha, Kurt Schwertsik and Heinz Karl Gruber, are in residence at the theatre. Despite its reputation for conservatism, Vienna was the crucible for many of the 20th century's most radical developments in music and the arts. Michael Berkeley explores the appealing and often ironic sounds of Vienna today with some of its most important artistic figures. Executive producer Dennis Marks, Producer Peter Maniura, Director Jane Walker Recorded at London (England). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano, and many others Duplicate of 007. Technical issues prevented digitizing. (Box 1, Item 06)
  Contents: Contents include excerpts from works by Hanns Eisler (Massnahme), Friedrich Cerha (Elegie, Keintate), Kurt Schwertsik (Rumba, Horn trio, Kurze Geschichte der Bourgeoisie) and Heinz Karl Gruber (Frankenstein).
  Digitized copies: Not reformatted
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 7, June 1987, 1 Betamax cassette; Title on container: 1987 BBC TV - Vienna Now (2) (NTSC) Almeida Festival: Vienna now. Introduced by Michael Berkeley. BBC TV production about the June 1987 Almeida Festival, with interviews with Pierre Audi, artistic director of the festival, and guest composers, Friedrich Cerha, Kurt Schwertsik and Heinz Karl Gruber. Executive producer Dennis Marks, producer Peter Maniura, director Jane Walker. Includes excerpts from interview with Pierre Audi. Kurt Schwertsik Tango performed by Mikhashoff. Presents History of 20th century music in Vienna, with historical footage. Recorded at London (England). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano and many others Durations: 26:43 NTSC format Includes Mikhashoff performing Cerha's Elegie at ca. 10:05. English subtitled for German interviews. (Box 1, Item 07)
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_007_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_007_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_007_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 04
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 8, 1987, 1 Betamax cassette 130; Title on container: 1987 Norwegian recording session Tape 1 Audio only from recording session, with multiple takes of some works. Recorded at Bergen (Norway). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Durations: 1:01:31; 1:12:24 Tape 1 of 3 PAL/F1 format (Box 1, Item 08)
  Contents include: Feldman, Morton: Intermission 5; Speech, Bernadette: To tango or not; Copland, Aaron: Sonnets; Berkman, Robert: Thorn-torn lips; Thomson, Virgil: Sentimental tango; Loudova, Ivana: Tango; Hovhaness, Alan: Visionary landscapes I
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_008_01am.wav; ubmu0001_8_008_02am.wav
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_008_01pm.wav; ubmu0001_8_008_02pm.wav
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_008_01sc.mp3; ubmu0001_8_008_02sc.mp3
  DVD or CD disc number 05-06
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 9, 1987, 1 Betamax cassette 130; Title on container: 1987 Norwegian recording session Tape 2 Audio only from recording session, with multiple takes of some works. Recorded at Bergen (Norway). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Durations: 49:09; 55:03 Tape 2 of 3 PAL/F1 format (Box 1, Item 09)
  Contents include: White, John: Piano sonata no. 108; Thomson, Virgil: Sentimental tango; Copland, Aaron: Moods; Nancarrow, Conlon: Tango?; Riegger, Wallingford: Blue voyage; Shapey, Ralph: unnamed work (Passacaglia?)
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_009_01am.wav; ubmu0001_8_009_02am.wav
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_009_01pm.wav; ubmu0001_8_009_02pm.wav
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_009_01sc.mp3; ubmu0001_8_009_02sc.mp3
  DVD or CD disc number 07-08
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 10, 1987, 1 Betamax cassette 130; Title on container: 1987 Norwegian recording session Tape 3 Audio only from recording session, with multiple takes of some works. Recorded at Bergen (Norway). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano Durations: 50:02; 58:37 Tape 3 of 3 PAL/F1 format (Box 1, Item 10)
  Contents include: Liszt, Franz: Resignazione -- In festo transfigurationis Domini nostri Jesu Christi -- Wiegenlied -- Other works --Richard Wagner Venezia; Shapey, Ralph: Tango variations; Riegger, Wallingford: unnamed work; Feldman, Morton: Palais de Mari
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_010_01am.wav; ubmu0001_8_010_02am.wav
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_010_01pm.wav; ubmu0001_8_010_02pm.wav
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_010_01sc.mp3; ubmu0001_8_010_02sc.mp3
  DVD or CD disc number 09-10
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 11, 14 March 1988, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival 1988: Cage, Scelsi and Hauer Title frame: Cage, Scelsi, Hauer, Burchfield Art Center, Monday, March 14. Recorded at Burchfield Art Center (Buffalo, N.Y.). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, Anthony de Mare, Frieda and Stephen Manes, piano; Robert Black, bass guitar; Frances-Marie Uitti, cello; Isabelle Ganz, mezzo-soprano; Carol Plantamura, soprano Durations: 1:48:59 1st 6:20 just ambient setting. Very dark. (Box 1, Item 11)
  Contents: Cage, John: … from Finnegan's wake -- The wonderful widow of eighteen springs -- North upon Nacht -- ASLSP -- composed improvisation for Steinberger bass guitar; Hauer, Josef Matthias: Labyrinthine dance op.3; Cage, John: Etudes boreales -- A flower; Scelsi, Giacinto: CKCKC; Cage, John: Souvenir; Scelsi, Giacinto: YGGHUR; Cage, John: Litany for the whale
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_011_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_011_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_011_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 11
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 12, 18 March 1988, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival 1988: Music for words, Pierre Audi directs works by Mauricio Kagel and Sylvano Bussotti Title frame: North American New Music Festival 1988 … Friday, March 18 Tralfamadore Café: Music for words: Pierre Audi directs. Recorded at Tralfamadore Café (Buffalo, N.Y.). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano and actor; Frances-Marie Uitti, David Sims, cello; Jan Williams, percussion; Paul Schmidt, actor; Pauline Vaillancourt, soprano; Pierre Audi, director; Robert Fernandez, percussion (Match) Durations: 1:24:35 Very dark; camera pans with subjects in theatrical works. (Box 1, Item 12)
  Contents: Kagel:, Mauricio: Match (19:20) -- Presentation (to 40:55); Bussotti, Sylvano: Pianobar pour Phaedre
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_012_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_012_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_012_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 12
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 13, 3 March 1988, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival 3/13/88: Arditti String Quartet Title frame: North American New Music Festival. Sunday, March 13. Recorded at Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Buffalo, N.Y.). Performers: Arditti String Quartet: Irwin Arditti, David Alberman, violin; Levine Andrade, viola; Rohan de Saram, cello Durations: 1:44:00 There is ambient sound only for the first 1:34. (Box 1, Item 13)
  Contents: Nash, Peter Paul: String quartet; Speach: Pentamenta; Felder, David: Third face; Hoyland, Vic: String quartet; Ferneyhough, Brian: String quartet no. 3
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_013_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_013_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_013_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 13
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 14, 14 March 1988, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival March 14 1988: John Cage Lecture on anarchy Recorded at Frederick C. and Alice Slee Chamber Hall (State University of New York at Buffalo). Performers: John Cage, speaker Durations: 1:26:08 At the beginning there seem to be 2 audio tracks: one clear, the other via the room ambience which contains so much reverberation it is extremely difficult to understand Cage's words. The clear track stops ca. 2:30. Video very dark. (Box 1, Item 14)
  Contents: Cage, John: Lecture on anarchy
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_014_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_014_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_014_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 14
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 15, 14 March 1988, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: John Cage - Lecture on Anarchy audio dub Audio only. Recorded at Frederick C. and Alice Slee Chamber Hall (State University of New York at Buffalo). Performers: John Cage, speaker Durations: 47:45; 36:28 Audio only. It is much better than the audio on Tape 14 but has to be checked to see if complete Sounds like this is directly from the mike feed without room reverberation. (Box 1, Item 15)
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_015_01am.wav; ubmu0001_8_015_02am.wav
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_015_01pm.wav; ubmu0001_8_015_02pm.wav
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_015_01sc.mp3; ubmu0001_8_015_02sc.mp3
  DVD or CD disc number 15-16
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 16, 11 March 1988, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival 1988: Music for words, Peter Sellers [sic] directs Paul Schmidt Music for words: Peter Sellars directs Paul Schmidt Recorded at Pfeifer Theater (State University of New York at Buffalo). Performers: Peter Sellars, director; Yvar Mikhashoff, Mark Bennett, Elizabeth Swados, and Paul Schmidt, performers Durations: 1:01:31 Video very dark. (Box 1, Item 16)
  Contents: Bennett, Mark: The drunken boat; Glass, Philip: Einstein on the beach. Paris speech; Hassell, Jon: Zangezi; Swados, Elizabeth: The beautiful lady
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_016_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_016_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_016_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 17
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 17, March 1988, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: Excerpt performances at the 1988 North American New Music Festival, presented by SUNY at Buffalo and Hallwalls North American New Music Festival 1988 presented by the Dept. of Music, SUNY at Buffalo in cooperation with Hallwalls Inc., Jan Williams, Yvar Mikhashoff, artistic directors, Donald Metz, administrative director, videography, Seth Tamrowski and James H. Braun. Recorded at Buffalo (N.Y.). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, piano; Arditti String Quartet; Robert Fernandez, Frances-Marie Uitti; Don Metz, and Paul Schmidt Durations: 1:01:29 (Box 1, Item 17)
  Contents: Cage, John: Souvenir; Scelsi, Giacinto: YGGHUR; Felder, David: Third face; Hoyland, Vic: String quartet; Zappa, Frank: Persona non grata; [Fernandez, Robert: Katibo]; Glass, Philip: Einstein on the beach
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_017_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_017_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_017_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 18
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 18, 11 April 1989, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival 1989 April 11: The music of George Crumb Recorded at Frank B. and Cameron Baird Music Hall (State University of New York at Buffalo). Performers: Stephen Manes, piano, Frieda Manes, piano, and Chamber Concerts Canada Ensemble Durations: 1:09:31 Semi-staged with adult and child female dancers. (Box 1, Item 18)
  Contents: Crumb: Zeitgeist (through 37:30) -- Ancient voices of children (begins at 39:40)
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_018_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_018_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_018_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 19
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 19, 13 April 1989, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival 1989 April 13: The music of Frederic Rzewski Recorded at Frederick C. and Alice Slee Chamber Hall (State University of New York at Buffalo). Performers: Aki Takahashi, Frederic Rzewski, piano; The California E.A.R. Unit: Amy Knowles, Arthur Jarvinen, Rand Steiger, James Rohrig, Dorothy Stone, Erika Duke, Gaylord Mowrey, and Lorna Little Durations: 1:43:59 (Box 1, Item 19)
  Contents: Rzewski, Frederic: Spots -- Turtle and the crane -- Mary's dream -- Spots -- Mayn Yingele -- Coming together
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_019_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_019_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_019_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 20
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 20, 12 April 1989, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival Concert II Recorded at Frederick C. and Alice Slee Chamber Hall (State University of New York at Buffalo). Performers: California E.A.R. Unit: Amy Knowles, Arthur Jarvinen, Rand Steiger, percussion; James Rohrig, clarinet; Dorothy Stone, flute; Erika Duke, cello; Gaylord Mowrey, Lorna Little, piano Durations: 1:24:27 (Box 1, Item 20)
  Contents: Torke, Michael: The yellow pages; Carter, Elliott: Enchanted preludes; Boulez, Pierre: Derive; Lang, David: Illumination rounds; Fernandez, Robert: Tentacles; Jarvinen, Arthur: The seven golden vampires; Steiger, Rand: 13 loops
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_020_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_020_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_020_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 21
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 21, 14 April 1989, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival April 14 1989 Recorded at Hallwalls (Buffalo, N.Y.). Performers: Robert Ashley, piano; Blue 'Gene' Tyranny, piano; Tom Buckner, vocals Durations: 1:35:14 (Box 2, Item 21)
  Contents: Ashley, Robert: My brother called
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_021_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_021_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_021_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 22
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 22, 16 April 1989, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival April 16 1989 (1) Recorded at Hallwalls (Buffalo, N.Y.). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, Aki Takahashi, piano; Paul Schmidt, actor Durations: 25:12 Tape 1 of 2 With projected video (Box 2, Item 22)
  Contents: Satie, Erik: Relâche
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_022_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_022_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_022_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 23
- Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Video Recordings, Item 23, 16 April 1989, 1 VHS cassette T-120; Title on container: North American New Music Festival April 16 1989 (2) Recorded at Hallwalls (Buffalo, N.Y.). Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, Aki Takahashi, piano; Paul Schmidt, actor Durations: 1:33:14 Tape 2 of 2 Program begins at circa 2:20. (Box 2, Item 23)
  Contents: Satie, Erik: Parade (version for 2 pianos) -- Sports and diversions; Cage, John: Two indeterminate variations; Satie, Erik: Socrate, transcribed by Cage; Cage, John: Furniture music etcetera
  Preservation archival master: ubmu0001_8_023_am.mov
  Production master: ubmu0001_8_023_pm.mov
  Service copy: ubmu0001_8_023_sc.mov
  DVD or CD disc number 24